Guide to the Clydie F. Scarborough Papers, 1918-1984, undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Clydie F. Scarborough papers 1918-1984, undated
Scarborough, Clydie Fullwood
Extent: 950 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.01143
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Biographical Note
Grandchild of Fabius and Adelle Fullwood, former slaves of Opilaka, Ala.; manager of Scarborough Nursery School, Inc.; and an active participant in civic, religious, social, and community organizations of Durham, N.C.
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence, financial papers, legal and administrative papers, clippings, writings, and printed material pertaining to the Scarborough Nursery School, Talladega College, the United Fund Agency and other non-profit organizations, and John C. Scarborough, Mrs. Scarborough's husband. The collection documents, in part, the work of Mrs. Scarborough to provide effective and healthy daycare for African-American children in Durham, N.C. Includes photographs of the Scarborough Nursery School, a 1946 report from the Education Planning Council for Durham, N.C. City Schools, Fullwood family genealogical papers, and documents from the North Carolina Daycare Association.
Subject Headings
Fullwood family; Scarborough, John C.; United Fund of Durham and Durham County; Scarborough Nursery School; Talledega College; North Carolina Daycare Association; Afro-american women; Day care centers -- North Carolina; Durham (N.C.) -- Schools; Photographs
Contents of Collection
- Clydie F. Scarborough Papers, 1918-1984
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Inc.: General, 1919, Mar.-1984, Feb., undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings: General, 1954, Mar.-1973, Oct., undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1923, Sept.-1989, Jan., undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Daycare:
    - General, 1943, May-1973, Sept., undated (Box 1)
    - Clippings, 1958, Sept.-1979, Aug., undated (Box 1)
  - Financial: Clydie's accident, tax information, general receipts, 1933, Jan.-1988, Sept., undated (Box 1)
  - Fullwood, Robert F.: Estate and funeral information, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Genealogy, 1983, July-1989, undated (Box 1)
  - Legal papers: Clydie's settlement for women's compensation from Scarborough Nursery School, Inc., 1977, July-1978, undated (Box 1)
  - North Carolina Day Care Association:
    - Administrative papers, undated (Box 1)
    - Executive Board meeting, 1972, Nov.-1974, Sept. (Box 1)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous, 1965, June, undated (Box 2)
  - Pictures:
    - Family, 1975-1989, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Scarborough Nursery School, Inc., 1937-1982, Apr., undated (Box 2)
  - Printed material, 1926-1988, July, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - St. Joseph's A.M.E. Church: Printed material, 1953, Sept.-1985, Feb., undated (Box 3)
  - Scarborough Nursery School, Inc.:
    - Administrative papers, 1952, Sept.-1980, May, undated (Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1957, Aug.-1984, May, undated (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1945, Apr.-1982, May, undated (Box 3)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 3)
    - Financial, 1940, Sept.-1982, July, undated (Box 3)
    - Printed material, 1945, Aug.-1986, June, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Writings and speeches, 1954, June, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Scarborough, John C.:
    - Personal, 1873, June-1972, Feb., undated (Box 3)
  - Scarborough and Hargett Funeral directors, 1974, Feb.-1988, June, undated (Box 3)
  - Stanford, Peter: Grandson of Clydie, 1953, Mar.-1989, Feb., undated (Box 3)
  - Talledega College:
    - Alumni information, 1972, Apr.-1979, June, undated (Box 3)
    - Photographs, 1922, undated (Box 4)
    - Printed material, 1920, Mar.-1988 (Box 4)
  - United Fund Agency and other non-profit organizations:
    - Clippings, undated (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1951, June-1959, Oct., undated (Box 4)
    - Printed material, 1949, Apr.-1981, June, undated (Box 4)
  - Writings and Speeches: General, undated (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1944, 1945, undated (Box 4)
  - Oversize Materials
    - Clippings, General, 1951, Sept.-1972, Sept., undated (Oversize-box 99)
    - Correspondence, Personal, 1923, Sept.-1926, June (Oversize-box 99)
    - Daycare, General, 1943, May-1973, Sept., undated (Oversize-box 99)
    - Daycare, Clippings, 1951, Apr.-1978, Feb. undated (Oversize-box 99)
    - Printed Material, 1950, Apr.-1982, Apr. (Oversize-box 99)
    - Scarborough Nursery School, Inc.
      - Clippings, 1957, Aug.-1982, Apr., undated (Oversize-box 99)
      - Photographs, 1932, undated (Oversize-box 99)
    - Stanford, Peter, 1953 (Oversize-box 99)
    - United Fund and other non-profit agencies, clippings, 1950, May-1965, Apr., undated (Oversize-box 99)
    - United Fund and other non-profit agencies, printed material, 1949, Apr.-1981, June, undated (Opaperfolder OC:I:2)